Email: liliwfxa@gmail.com Mobile: +1-817-734-9751

Portfolio LinkedIn Github

Summary

As an entrepreneur with extensive experience in e-commerce and real estate analytics, I led my startup to achieve \$6 million in sales. Currently, I am enhancing my business acumen and data analysis skills at the University of Washington, with the goal of continuing to influence business strategies and decision-making.

Work Experience

Co-founder and Data Analyst

Seattle

ATMT: Start-up E-commerce Specialized in Cosmetics

2016 - 2023

- \bullet Spearheaded A/B testing and targeted SEO strategy, driving a 30% increase in website traffic and generating \$6 million in sales.
- Implemented CRM-informed, data-driven segmentation and targeted marketing to boost subscriptions by 50% and increase quarterly sales by 30%, yielding an additional \$1 million in revenue.
- Utilized ad bidding and data analysis to identify and amplify market potential of products, continuously optimized promotional strategies, creating a monthly top-selling lipstick with over 5,000 units sold.

Marketing Analyst

Changsha, China

Shenzhen World union Consultancy: Top 10 Chinese Real Estate Consulting Firms

2012 - 2016

- Applied machine learning to pinpoint top determinants of property prices in Shenzhen, a first-tier city in China, resulting in data-driven product alignment and a 10% surge in sales revenue for Vanke.
- Led data normalization efforts, achieving a 9% increase in sales and 50% less data processing time by enhancing data quality and reliability through cross-departmental collaboration.
- Developed and implemented KPI dashboards, empowering shareholders to make data-driven decisions.

Sales Manager

Changsha, China

Shenzhen World union Consultancy: Top 10 Chinese Real Estate Consulting Firms

2010 - 2012

- Analyzed customer data to tailor sales approaches, leading to personal sales of \$10 million and earning the title of 'Annual Sales Champion' twice.
- Established a performance framework and motivational policies, driving the team to a \$30 million sales.

PROJECTS

Alibaba Post-Promotion Optimization - Project Lead

December 2021

- Technologies: Python, K-means cluster, AB testing, Data Analysis, Live-Stream Marketing
- Achievement: Identified and resolved a critical e-commerce conversion funnel issue, optimizing product pages (CRO) and implementing Taobao live-stream marketing with effective CTAs.
- Impact: Successfully reduced the cart abandonment rate to 90.5% and doubled the conversion rate to 4%, leading to a substantial increase in sales and improved customer engagement.

Advanced Used Car Valuation Web Platform - Project Lead

December 2023

- Technologies: Python, Streamlit, Random Forest, Causal analysis, Runway, Chatbase, DALL.E.
- Achievement: Successfully launched an AI-driven model to predict used car prices, enhancing user decision-making; Created a custom AI chatbox to field user questions on used cars, improving engagement; Integrated cutting-edge AI technology, elevating the platform's functionality and user experience.
- **Impact**: Boosted platform engagement and established the site as a go-to solution for accurate car valuations and information.

SKILL

- Programming: SQL, Python, R
- Data Visualization: Excel, Tableau, Power BI
- Modeling: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Random Forest, K-means Clustering, Causal Random Forest
- Certification: Google Data Analytics
- Strategic Analytical Skills: Critical Thinking, Problem-solving, Statistical Analysis, Leadership

EDUCATION

University of Washington – Michael G. Foster School of Business

Seattle, WA